<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Docs on Hues of Intelligence</title>
    <link>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on Hues of Intelligence</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://hues.mpilosov.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://hues.mpilosov.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Michael Pilosov</copyright><atom:link href="http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Baseline: UMAP</title>
      <link>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/umap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/umap/</guid>
      <description>Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection is a statistical technique for reducing the dimension of a space. It operates by looking for a low-dimensional projection of the data that has the &amp;ldquo;closest possible equivalent fuzzy topological structure.&amp;rdquo; In other words, it is designed to preserve the relative distances between points in space before and after projection.
This fit well with the intended task to transform RGB space into a 1-dimensional space in which we can interrogate color orderings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervised Learning</title>
      <link>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/supervised/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/supervised/</guid>
      <description>In the supervised learning regime, the true values of hue were presented in the form of &amp;ldquo;correct answers,&amp;rdquo; allowing the neural network to learn the transformation between RGB and Hue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Unsupervised</title>
      <link>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/unsupervised/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/unsupervised/</guid>
      <description>In the first unsupervised set, the objective was defined as preserving the relative distances amongst examples in the same batch. In other words, for a given set of examples, the model would compare how far apart each pair of colors were in RGB space and in the discovered 1-dimensional space. It tried to keep these pair-wise distances similar to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchoring the Unsupervised</title>
      <link>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/anchors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hues.mpilosov.com/docs/anchors/</guid>
      <description>In the second unsupervised set, the objective was similar to the first, but instead of comparing distances amongst examples in the same training batch, a fixed set of colors was used, acting as anchors. This removes one of the elements of randomness in evaluating the objective to optimize, and creates less of a dependence on batch size in the unsupervised learning approach.
These results tended to be more consistent in the orderings that the machine discovered, creating results that appear to leverage luminosity and color information together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
